Dear brothers and sisters.
사랑하는 형제 자매 여러분.
Today...
오늘...
We gather to pray
우리는 기도하기 위해 모였습니다
for the eternal rest
영원한 안식을 위하여
of the late Kim Mi Ran, Julia.
故 김미란 줄리아.
Though her life on this earth has ended,
그녀의 이 땅에서의 삶은 끝났지만,
let us remember that a new life has begun in heaven,
그걸 기억하자 천국에서 새로운 삶이 시작되었습니다.
and fill our hearts with hope.
그리고 우리 마음을 희망으로 채우십시오.
Julia was a wonderful mother,
Julia는 훌륭한 어머니였습니다.
wife, and...
아내, 그리고...
friend.
친구.
This means
이는 다음을 의미합니다.
that Julia was never alone,
줄리아는 결코 혼자가 아니었습니다.
and even now,
그리고 지금도,
she is being accompanied by her loving husband,
그녀는 사랑하는 남편과 함께 있고,
daughter,
딸,
son,
아들,
and all those who cherished her.
그리고 그녀를 아껴준 모든 사람들.
Letting go of someone we love is
사랑하는 사람을 떠나보내는 것은
deeply painful and difficult.
매우 고통스럽고 어렵습니다.
But the Lord gives us hope.
그러나 주님은 우리에게 소망을 주십니다.
We pray that the Lord may comfort us
주님께서 우리를 위로해 주시기를 기도합니다
and grant peace
그리고 평화를 주소서
and grace to all who remain.
남은 모든 사람에게 은혜를 베푸소서.
Amen.
아멘.
I'll get going.
나는 갈 것이다.
Thank you for coming.
와주셔서 감사합니다.
Gosh...
이런...
My poor sister.
내 불쌍한 여동생.
Bye.
안녕.
She went through so much, and now she's gone...
그 사람은 너무 많은 일을 겪었고 이제 세상을 떠났어요...
You poor things.
불쌍한 것들아.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Yeah, sure.
응, 물론이지.
He looks like a walking corpse.
그는 걷는 시체처럼 보입니다.
As thank you gifts? Let me think...
감사 선물로? 생각해보자...
Jun Kyung, take good care of him.
준경 씨, 잘 보살펴주세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
- Take care, you two. - 30-count is more...
- 두 분 모두 조심하세요. - 30카운트가 더...
practical and durable...
실용적이고 내구성이 좋습니다..
40-count is softer and more premium...
40카운트가 더 부드럽고 고급스러워요..
Oh, you're having a first birthday party.
아, 돌잔치 중이시군요.
They don't look that sad.
그다지 슬퍼 보이지는 않네요.
It's like...
마치...
they're just here to take care of business.
그들은 단지 사업을 처리하기 위해 여기에 있습니다.
Everyone grieves in their own way.
모두가 자신의 방식으로 슬퍼합니다.
[Handong Catholic Church]
[한동성당]
I'll get going.
나는 갈 것이다.
- Take care. - Thank you.
- 잘 지내세요. - 감사합니다.
A lot of people came.
많은 사람들이 왔습니다.
Yeah.
응.
It would've been nice if they'd come while she was alive.
좋았을 텐데 그녀가 살아 있는 동안 그들이 왔더라면.
[The late Kim Mi Ran]
[故 김미란]
[The late Kim Mi Ran, Julia]
[故 김미란, 줄리아]
Let's go.
가자.
Your mom needs to rest now.
엄마는 이제 쉬셔야 해요.
I'll stay a little longer with Jun Seo.
저는 준서랑 좀 더 같이 있을게요.
Don't be sad. I'm here.
슬퍼하지 마세요. 나는 여기 있다.
Don't lie! You saw her!
거짓말하지 마세요! 당신은 그녀를 봤어!
What are you talking about? I didn't!
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요? 나는하지 않았다!
You did!
그랬어요!
There's been a misunderstanding. Please calm down.
오해가 생겼습니다. 진정하세요.
Then let's check the security camera.
그럼 보안 카메라를 확인해 볼까요?
- Hey... - Let's check it now!
- 안녕... - 지금 확인해 보세요!
- Sir, please calm down. - Hey!
- 선생님, 진정하세요. - 여기요!
This pervert was staring at my girl's legs!
이 변태가 내 여자 다리를 노려보고 있었어!
Seo Jun Seo!
서준서!
What did I do wrong?
내가 뭘 잘못했나요?
Did you really have to do that here? You embarrassed me.
꼭 여기서 해야 했나요? 당신은 나를 당황하게 만들었습니다.
Did you really have to wear such a skirt to a place like this?
꼭 입어야 했나? 이런 곳에 이런 스커트를?
What?
무엇?
That outfit isn't appropriate for a place like this.
그 옷은 어울리지 않아 이런 곳을 위해.
I didn't dress like this because of where we are.
나 이런 옷 안 입었는데 우리가 있는 곳 때문에.
This is the real me.
이것이 진짜 나입니다.
I hate it!
싫어!
I hate that you dress like that every day.
네가 매일 그렇게 입는 게 싫어.
I hate that you post outfits like that on social media, too.
난 당신이 그런 의상을 게시하는 것을 싫어 소셜미디어에서도요.
And it pisses me off when guys hit on you after seeing that.
그리고 남자들이 그러면 날 화나게 해 그걸 본 후에 당신을 때렸어요.
You really make me feel so alone.
당신은 정말 나를 너무 외롭게 만듭니다.
Hey, Yoon Sol.
안녕하세요, 윤솔님.
Yoon Sol!
윤솔!
I ruined it.
내가 망쳤어.
My mom's last day.
엄마의 마지막 날.
I thought there'd be another day.
나는 또 다른 날이 있을 것이라고 생각했다.
Your mom and I...
너희 엄마와 나는...
We weren't anything special, but...
우리는 특별하지 않았지만...
I thought we'd be okay, just like this...
이대로라면 괜찮을 줄 알았는데...
Grow old together.
함께 늙어가세요.
Take trips sometimes to nice places.
가끔 좋은 곳으로 여행을 떠나보세요.
Eat ice cream while watching the sunset side by side.
아이스크림을 먹어라 나란히 일몰을 감상하면서.
Sing songs together.
함께 노래를 불러보세요.
Even ride the yacht your mom always wanted to try.
요트도 타보고 네 엄마는 항상 시도해 보고 싶었어.
It's sad when someone dies, but...
사람이 죽으면 슬프지만...
All the things they wanted to do...
그들이 하고 싶었던 모든 일들...
All the things your mom and I planned to do together...
네 엄마의 모든 것 그리고 같이 하기로 했는데...
It feels like all of that disappears too.
그것도 다 사라지는 것 같은 느낌.
Excuse me, could you pull over for a moment?
실례합니다. 잠시 차를 세워 주시겠어요?
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
Dad?
아빠?
Go first.
먼저 가세요.
The person you're calling is unavailable.
지금 전화하신 분은 부재중입니다.
Please leave a message.
메시지를 남겨주세요.
Is everything all right?
모든 것이 괜찮습니까?
Her cervix is dilating well, but the contractions are irregular.
자궁경부가 잘 확장되고 있고, 그러나 수축은 불규칙하다.
Hey, I'm talking about you.
이봐, 나는 당신에 대해 이야기하고 있습니다.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
Of course I am.
물론이죠.
There you go again... pretending.
또... 척하는 거죠.
How could you possibly be okay?
어떻게 괜찮을 수 있니?
The neighbor's guitar was kind of comforting.
이웃의 기타가 좀 위안이 됐어요.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
When someone is born, someone else dies.
누군가 태어나면 누군가는 죽는다.
Someone pays me a salary,
누군가 나에게 월급을 주고,
and I just do my job.
난 그냥 내 일을 할 뿐이에요.
You're really something else.
당신은 정말 다른 사람입니다.
I keep my work and personal life strictly separate.
일과 사생활은 내가 지킨다 엄격하게 분리됩니다.
Got it?
알았어요?
Honey, should I step outside?
여보, 나 밖으로 나가볼까?
Please don't go.
제발 가지 마세요.
You can't stay like this. Push.
이대로 있을 수는 없어요. 푸시.
Breathe. Don't hold it in.
숨 쉬다. 참지 마세요.
Honey, breathe!
여보, 숨 쉬어요!
Your wife needs to breathe, not you.
숨을 쉬어야 할 사람은 당신이 아니라 당신의 아내입니다.
Honey! I think I'm dying!
꿀! 나 죽어가는 것 같아!
You're not going to die. Don't worry.
당신은 죽지 않을 것입니다. 괜찮아요.
There's no one who can give birth for you.
당신을 대신해서 낳아줄 사람은 아무도 없습니다.
Are you going to look that weak in front of your daughter?
그렇게 약해 보이나요? 딸 앞에서?
You don't want to end up the kind of mom
넌 그런 엄마가 되고 싶지 않아
who loses her legs in a rainy car accident, right?
다리를 잃은 사람 비 오는 교통사고에서요, 그렇죠?
Or a mom who argues with her daughter...
아니면 딸과 다투는 엄마...
And dies of a brain hemorrhage...
그리고 뇌출혈로 사망..
Without ever making up with her.
그녀와 화해하지도 않고.
You don't want to be that kind of mother.
당신은 그런 엄마가 되고 싶지 않아요.
What are you even talking about?
무슨 말을 하는 거야?
[Reception Office]
[접수실]
Hey.
안녕.
You said you keep work and personal life strictly separate.
계속 일한다고 했잖아 개인 생활과 엄격하게 분리됩니다.
The whole hospital is buzzing.
병원 전체가 웅성거립니다.
They say Dr. Seo tried a new delivery method.
서 박사가 새로운 전달법을 시도했다고 합니다.
The patient must've been really confused.
환자분 정말 당황하셨겠네요.
You kept shouting "daughter" when it was a son.
아들인데 계속 '딸'이라고 외치셨어요.
Bet the baby was confused too.
아기도 혼란스러워했을 것입니다.
Like, "Mom, was I a girl?"
"엄마, 제가 여자였나요?"
I'm not in the mood for jokes.
나는 농담할 기분이 아니다.
I'm not joking.
농담하는 게 아닙니다.
I was giving you a compliment.
나는 당신에게 칭찬을 주고 있었습니다.
Even cold-blooded Seo Jun Kyung
냉혈한 서준경마저도
has a heart after all.
결국 마음이 있습니다.
Yeah, you might've looked a little crazy...
응, 좀 미친 것처럼 보였을 수도 있지...
But so what?
하지만 그래서 어쩌죠?
You did well.
잘했어요.
Did my mom love me?
엄마는 나를 사랑했나요?
When I think about it,
생각해보면,
I don't think
내 생각엔 아닌 것 같아
I have ever heard her say she loved me.
나는 그녀가 나를 사랑한다고 말하는 것을 들어 본 적이 있습니다.
Gosh.
이런.
You raise daughters with all your heart,
당신은 온 마음을 다해 딸을 키우고,
and this is what they end up saying.
그리고 이것이 그들이 말하는 결론입니다.
Have you ever told your mom you loved her?
엄마에게 사랑한다고 말한 적이 있나요?
I thought I'd at least get to share 40 more meals with my mom.
적어도 공유할 수 있을 거라 생각했는데 엄마와 함께 40번의 식사를 더 합니다.
But look.
하지만 보세요.
She stayed irresponsible till the very end.
그녀는 끝까지 무책임했습니다.
Hey, I'm never ever
이봐, 난 절대 그런 적 없어
going to die before my daughter.
내 딸보다 먼저 죽을 거야.
That's impressive.
인상적이네요.
A mom whose goal is to outlive her daughter.
딸보다 오래 사는 것이 목표인 엄마.
Pretty great, huh?
정말 멋지죠?
- I think I'm amazing. - You really are.
- 내 생각엔 내가 대단한 것 같아. - 정말 그렇군요.
Jun Kyung, that's enough drinking.
준경 씨, 충분히 마셨어요.
You're heading home already?
벌써 집에 가는 거야?
Look at this.
이것 좀 보세요.
My daughters are blowing up my phone.
내 딸들이 내 전화를 폭파하고 있어요.
Don't answer it.
대답하지 마세요.
Don't go.
가지 마세요.
Hi, sweetie.
안녕, 얘야.
Yeah.
응.
Is your Dad drunk?
아빠가 술에 취하셨나요?
[Mom]
[엄마]
[My daughter]
[내 딸]
Mom.
엄마.
Jun Kyung?
준경?
I was bringing in the laundry.
세탁물을 가져오고 있었습니다.
It's raining now.
지금 비가 내리고 있습니다.
You forgot again? You're so scatterbrained.
또 잊으셨나요? 당신은 너무 산만해요.
Where did you put it?
어디에 두셨나요?
Mom, where are you now?
엄마, 지금 어디 계세요?
Almost there.
거의 다 왔습니다.
Stop rushing me.
더 이상 서두르지 마세요.
I told you to send it by courier. It's raining.
택배로 보내라고 했어요. 비가 오네요.
A courier? Do you know how much that costs?
택배? 비용이 얼마나 되는지 아시나요?
- I'll be faster. - So where are you now?
- 제가 더 빠를게요. - 그럼 지금 어디 계시나요?
- I just passed Howon Station. - Okay, I'll head out now.
- 방금 호원역을 지나갔습니다. - 알았어, 이제 나갈게.
Mom, where are you?
엄마, 어디 계세요?
Hurry up.
서둘러요.
I told you not to come.
내가 오지 말라고 했잖아.
I told you not to come...
오지 말라고 했는데...
since it's raining.
비가 오니까.
I told you not to come.
내가 오지 말라고 했잖아.
It's not your fault.
그것은 당신의 잘못이 아닙니다.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
Don't cry, Jun Kyung.
울지 마, 준경아.
It's not your fault.
그것은 당신의 잘못이 아닙니다.
- It's raining again. - I know.
- 또 비가 오네요. - 알아요.
- Let's go. - Yeah.
- 갑시다. - 응.
What should we grab for dinner?
저녁으로 무엇을 챙겨야 할까요?
Hey!
여기요!
Seo Jun Seo!
서준서!
[Fast-Pitch Ball Game]
[빠른 피치 볼 게임]
Please, just let me hit it once.
제발 한 번만 쳐보도록 해주세요.
Just once!
딱 한 번만!
Geez...
이런...
Is anyone...
누구라도...?
Is anyone there?
거기 누구 없어요?
- Please. - What's going on?
- 제발. - 무슨 일이에요?
Mister, please help me.
아저씨, 도와주세요.
- I can't move my neck. - What's going on in the rain?
- 목을 움직일 수 없어요. - 비오는 날 무슨 일이 일어나고 있나요?
You again.
또 당신.
Yeah.
응.
Oh my.
아, 이런.
I forgot my door code.
출입문 비밀번호를 잊어버렸어요.
Funny, huh?
재미있지 않나요?
You can ask your husband to open it.
남편에게 열어달라고 요청할 수 있습니다.
My husband?
내 남편?
Oh, right.
아, 그렇죠.
Oh, my husband...
아, 남편...
He's on a business trip.
그는 출장 중입니다.
Like, far away.
멀리 떨어져 있습니다.
Then you can call and ask him.
그러면 그 사람에게 전화해서 물어보면 됩니다.
Oh, perfect timing.
아, 타이밍이 딱이네요.
Where did I put my phone?
내가 전화기를 어디에 두었나요?
- Oh no. - It's ringing.
- 안 돼. - 벨이 울리고 있어요.
Here.
여기.
Hey, what was our door code?
야, 우리 문 비밀번호가 뭐였지?
The ER?
응급실?
Which hospital?
어느 병원?
Okay, I'm coming.
알았어, 갈게.
I'll drive you.
내가 운전해줄게.
I'm okay.
난 괜찮아.
- Isn't it urgent? - It is.
- 급한 일 아닌가요? - 그것은.
Get in here.
여기로 들어가세요.
What?
무엇?
- Whose car is that? - Mine.
- 저건 누구 차야? - 내 거.
Let's go.
갑시다.
- You said the ER, right? - Yeah...
- 응급실이라고 했지? - 응...
- It's my car. - Wait a second.
- 내 차야. - 잠깐만요.
That hurts.
아프다.
Oh, hi.
아, 안녕.
What, did you drink?
뭐, 마셨어?
Nice going.
잘 가겠습니다.
So your paper is about baseball fusion or something?
그래서 당신의 논문은 대략 야구 퓨전인가 뭔가?
Don't joke around. I'm in this much pain.
농담하지 마세요. 나는 이만큼 고통받고 있다.
The nurse already told me everything.
간호사는 이미 나에게 모든 것을 말해주었다.
You hurt yourself swinging at nothing.
아무것도 아닌 스윙으로 인해 상처를 입었습니다.
And they said you can take the neck brace off soon.
그리고 그들은 당신이 걸릴 수 있다고 말했다 곧 목 보호대가 풀릴 것이다.
I'm still not okay. I almost died.
나는 아직도 괜찮지 않다. 나는 거의 죽을 뻔했습니다.
The painkillers saved me.
진통제가 나를 구했습니다.
I was stupid to call you.
내가 너한테 전화한 게 바보같았어
You called me because of the bill, huh?
청구서 때문에 나한테 전화했지?
No. Don't pay it. Not a cent.
아니요. 지불하지 마세요. 1센트도 아닙니다.
Alright, then I'll go back with my wallet.
알았어, 그럼 지갑을 가지고 돌아갈게.
How can someone be so annoying?
누군가가 어떻게 그렇게 짜증날 수 있습니까?
Gosh.
이런.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
No.
아니요.
No, I really am.
아니요, 정말 그렇습니다.
Why are you crying?
왜 울고 있어요?
Don't cry, baby.
울지 마, 자기야.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
This is my fault.
이건 내 잘못이야.
Look at me.
나를 봐.
Sol, look at me.
솔, 나 좀 봐.
Don't cry.
울지 마세요.
What do I do...
난 어떡하지...
- I think I really love you. - Hug me.
- 내가 당신을 정말 사랑하는 것 같아요. - 안아주세요.
I love you more.
나는 당신을 더 사랑합니다.
Love you.
사랑해요.
Hello, Sol?
안녕, 솔?
Hello, sis.
안녕, 언니.
Hi.
안녕.
By the way,
그건 그렇고,
who is this?
이 사람은 누구입니까?
Huh?
뭐?
This is... well...
이건... 음...
May I ask your name?
이름을 물어봐도 될까요?
I'm Ju Do Hyun.
저는 유도현이에요.
This is Ju Do Hyun. He lives next door.
유도현입니다. 그는 옆집에 산다.
Why would the guy next door
옆집 남자는 왜?
come here at this hour?
이 시간에 여기로 오세요?
What?
무엇?
I was on a date...
데이트 중이었는데...
with your sister.
네 여동생이랑.
She seemed in a hurry, so I came with her.
그 사람이 급한 것 같아서 나도 같이 왔어요.
You shouldn't call it a date. He'll get the wrong idea.
데이트라고 부르면 안 돼요. 그는 잘못된 생각을 갖게 될 것입니다.
Sorry for joking like that...
농담해서 죄송해요...
when you have a husband.
남편이 있을 때.
I don't actually have a husband.
저는 사실 남편이 없어요.
I know.
알아요.
Is it that obvious?
그렇게 뻔한가요?
You're 36.
당신은 36세입니다.
A doctor at SEAH Women's Hospital...
세아여성병원 의사..
You have your parents and a younger brother.
부모님과 남동생이 있습니다.
You are 167cm tall,
키가 167cm입니다.
and your weight is... a little more than I expected.
그리고 당신의 몸무게는... 생각보다 좀 많네요.
Being pretty gets old after a couple of years.
예쁜 것도 몇 년 지나면 늙어가거든요.
You see it everywhere.
어디서나 볼 수 있습니다.
So this time...
그래서 이번엔...
I already booked a room.
이미 방을 예약했습니다.
At Cerati,
Cerati에서
there's an engine sound design team.
엔진사운드 디자인팀이 있습니다.
A pianist and a composer...
피아니스트이자 작곡가...
You want to sleep with me, huh?
나랑 자고 싶죠?
We just met today.
우리는 오늘 막 만났습니다.
It hasn't even been an hour.
한 시간도 안 됐어요.
Hey...
안녕...
Lower your voice.
목소리를 낮추세요.
Right, I guess that way we don't waste time
그렇습니다. 그러면 시간을 낭비하지 않을 것 같아요
and can tell if we're a match.
그리고 우리가 일치하는지 알 수 있습니다.
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
I'll pay.
결제하겠습니다.
You wasted your time on a girl you won't sleep with.
당신은 여자한테 시간을 낭비했어요 당신은 함께 자지 않을 것입니다.
No need to waste money too.
돈을 낭비할 필요도 없습니다.
You're rude till the very end.
마지막까지 무례하시군요.
It was a boring date,
지루한 데이트였지만
but you made it interesting.
하지만 당신은 그것을 흥미롭게 만들었습니다.
You were kind of impressive.
당신은 꽤 인상적이었습니다.
The way you downed your drink and just walked out.
네가 술을 마시는 방식 그리고 그냥 나갔습니다.
I'm not
나는 아니다
usually like that.
보통 그렇죠.
Yeah?
응?
But...
하지만...
maybe I am.
아마도 나는 그럴 것이다.
Want to listen to some music?
음악을 듣고 싶나요?
Something that boosts my confidence, please.
내 자신감을 높여줄 뭔가를 주세요.
Hold on a second.
잠깐만요.
Thanks.
감사해요.
Did you remember the door code?
문 비밀번호를 기억하시나요?
I'm glad I got a good neighbor like you.
당신처럼 좋은 이웃이 있어서 기뻐요.
But what do we do?
하지만 우리는 무엇을 합니까?
I won't be...
난 안 그럴거야...
your neighbor much longer.
당신의 이웃은 훨씬 더 오래갑니다.
I'm moving soon.
나는 곧 이사할 예정이다.
I see.
알겠어요.
That's a shame, right?
정말 부끄러운 일이군요, 그렇죠?
Now...
지금...
We probably won't...
우리는 아마하지 않을 것입니다 ...
even run into each other anymore.
더 이상 서로 마주치더라도.
How about we meet on purpose sometime?
우리 가끔 가끔 만나보는 건 어때요?
You booked a discounted rate,
할인된 가격으로 예약하셨는데요,
so the reservation is non-refundable.
따라서 예약은 환불되지 않습니다.
I'm sorry, but we can't offer a refund.
죄송합니다. 환불해드릴 수 없습니다.
As I said,
내가 말했듯이,
there's no wife for me to go with anymore.
더 이상 같이 갈 아내가 없어요.
I'm truly sorry,
정말 죄송해요.
but there's nothing we can do.
하지만 우리가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없어요.
We wish you a good journey.
좋은 여행 되시길 바랍니다.
That family always revolved around Julia.
그 가족은 항상 Julia를 중심으로 돌아갔습니다.
Their life, the children, everything.
그들의 삶, 아이들, 모든 것.
They raised them so fiercely, so well.
그들은 그들을 너무나 맹렬하게, 너무나 잘 키웠습니다.
I can't imagine how Raphael's managing on his own now.
라파엘이 어떻게 관리하는지 상상할 수 없습니다 지금은 혼자서.
It really worries me.
정말 걱정됩니다.
Raphael?
라파엘?
See you next time. Raphael?
다음에 또 만나요. 라파엘?
Raphael!
라파엘!
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I had something urgent and couldn't make it to the funeral.
급한 일이 있어서 그리고 장례식에도 못 갔어요.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
Julia held on for so long.
Julia는 오랫동안 버텼습니다.
It still doesn't feel real that she's gone so suddenly.
아직 실감이 나지 않아요 그 사람이 갑자기 가버렸다고.
I heard it was a beautiful funeral.
아름다운 장례식이었다고 들었습니다.
Just the right number of people.
딱 적당한 인원수에요.
And they said the priest's words were wonderful.
그리고 그들은 말했다 목사님의 말씀은 훌륭했습니다.
Losing a spouse is supposed to be
배우자를 잃는 것은 당연하다
the most stressful thing you can go through in life.
가장 스트레스 받는 일 당신은 인생에서 겪을 수 있습니다.
Are you holding up?
당신은 버티고 있습니까?
Please take this off. I don't need it.
이것을 벗겨주세요. 필요하지 않습니다.
Poor thing.
불쌍한 것.
Hi, again.
안녕하세요.
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
Oh my! What the...
이런! 뭐야...
What did you say earlier?
아까 뭐라고 말했어요?
"A beautiful funeral?"
"아름다운 장례식이요?"
What's wrong with you?
왜 그래?
What kind of...
어떤 종류의 ...
funeral is beautiful?
장례식이 아름답나요?
He must be insane.
그 사람은 미친 게 분명해요.
Oh, gosh!
아, 이런!
My goodness!
이럴 수가!
Stop it!
그만해요!
You're still here?
아직 여기 있나요?
You're okay, right?
괜찮아요?
Yes.
예.
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
Julia will always be with you, watching over you from heaven.
줄리아는 항상 당신과 함께 할 것입니다. 하늘에서 당신을 지켜보고 있습니다.
- Thank you. - Bye.
- 감사합니다. - 안녕.
You know...
아시죠...
It hasn't been that long since my mom passed.
엄마가 돌아가신 지 그리 오래되지 않았어.
Will it be okay to meet a guy at a time like this?
남자 만나도 괜찮을까 이럴 때?
No one's ever going to...
아무도 안 그럴 거예요...
show up right on cue and say,
신호가 오면 바로 나타나서 이렇게 말하세요.
"Hey, now's the perfect time for you to date."
"야, 지금이 데이트하기 딱 좋은 때야."
I still can't believe that
나는 아직도 그 말을 믿을 수 없다
you gave your number to a stranger
당신은 낯선 사람에게 전화번호를 알려줬어요
and not even a repair guy.
수리공도 아니고요.
For real?
진짜요?
No, it's just...
아니, 그냥...
when he said he was moving away,
그 사람이 이사 간다고 했을 때,
I panicked without even thinking.
나는 생각지도 못한 채 당황했다.
I must've lost my mind.
내가 정신을 잃은 게 틀림없어.
You'll know once you meet him.
그 사람을 만나보면 알게 될 거예요.
He's not asking you to marry him or have his kids.
그 사람이 너한테 결혼하자고 하는 게 아니야 아니면 그의 아이가 있거나.
- It's just a date. - True.
- 그냥 데이트일 뿐이에요. - 사실입니다.
Right?
그렇죠?
We did pick a place to meet. But...
우리는 만날 장소를 정했습니다. 하지만...
Wait, he's wearing a hoodie.
잠깐만요, 그 사람 후드티를 입고 있어요.
A hoodie?
후드티?
Have they already met?
그들은 이미 만났나요?
Am I overdressed?
내가 옷을 너무 많이 입었나요?
Hey, you never know.
이봐, 넌 절대 모르잖아.
He could be a hotshot startup CEO.
그는 핫한 스타트업 CEO가 될 수 있다.
Give me the phone.
전화 주세요.
Hello, Jun Kyung.
안녕하세요, 준경님.
Don't just say whatever pops into your head, okay?
그냥 터지는 말만 하지 마세요 네 머리 속으로 들어가, 알았지?
Don't think too much.
너무 많이 생각하지 마세요.
No, no. Just do whatever feels right.
아뇨, 아뇨. 그냥 옳다고 생각되는 대로 하세요.
Hang up. Bye.
끊으세요. 안녕.
Are you listening?
듣고 있나요?
Hello? Hello?
안녕하세요? 안녕하세요?
What?
무엇?
You were on a call, right?
통화 중이었죠, 그렇죠?
- Please... - You were on a call, huh?
- 제발... - 통화 중이었지?
Yeah.
응.
You're early.
일찍 왔네요.
Yeah, I got here a bit ahead of time.
응, 좀 일찍 도착했어.
This place gets crowded if we're late.
우리가 늦으면 이곳은 혼잡해집니다.
It's a little awkward, right?
조금 어색하죠?
Yeah?
응?
Yeah... kind of.
응... 일종의.
I guess it has to be.
그래야 할 것 같아요.
We've only run into each other by chance before.
우리는 서로 마주쳤을 뿐이야 예전에 우연히.
This is our first real meeting.
이것이 우리의 첫 번째 실제 만남입니다.
Isn't there anything you want to ask me?
나한테 물어보고 싶은 건 없나요?
I do know...
나는 알고있다 ...
a bit about you though.
하지만 당신에 대해 조금.
I guess...
아마도...
I know a little about you too.
나도 당신에 대해 조금 알고 있어요.
Like...
마치...
You seem younger than me.
당신은 나보다 젊어 보인다.
Around 35?
35쯤?
And you're obviously not married.
그리고 당신은 분명히 결혼하지 않았습니다.
If you were, you wouldn't be here.
만약 그랬다면 당신은 여기에 없었을 겁니다.
As for what you do...
당신이 하는 일에 관해서는...
I'm guessing something artistic.
뭔가 예술적인 것 같아요.
And probably not very lucrative.
그리고 아마도 그다지 수익성이 좋지 않을 것입니다.
- How did you know? - Wait, am I right?
- 어떻게 알았어? - 잠깐만요, 내 말이 맞나요?
He is pretty a good man.
그는 꽤 좋은 사람이에요.
He's kind of cute, in a way.
그는 어떤 면에서는 좀 귀엽습니다.
But...
하지만...
He's 35 and still doing music.
그는 35세인데 아직도 음악을 하고 있다.
That feels a little...
그 느낌이 좀...
It doesn't seem great as a job.
직업으로는 별로 좋지 않은 것 같습니다.
What kind of music does he do?
그는 어떤 종류의 음악을 합니까?
How should I put it...
어떻게 넣어야 할까요...
Just...
그냥...
A bit of everything.
모든 것.
I go with whatever I feel.
나는 내가 느끼는 대로 갑니다.
I do anything and everything.
나는 무엇이든 할 수 있습니다.
He even knows what he does.
그는 자신이 무엇을 하는지도 알고 있습니다.
Doesn't that remind you of someone?
누군가를 생각나게 하지 않나요?
Who?
WHO?
A guy still stuck in his rebel phase, long after everyone else grew out of it.
아직도 반항적인 단계에 머물러 있는 한 남자, 다른 사람들이 모두 성장한 지 오래되었습니다.
Seo Jun Seo.
서준서.
- So he doesn't make money? - You can tell just by looking.
- 그럼 그 사람은 돈을 못 벌어요? - 딱 봐도 알 수 있어요.
You should've asked things like,
다음과 같은 질문을 했어야 했는데,
"what's your annual income?"
"당신의 연간 수입은 얼마입니까?"
"Can you support yourself?"
"당신은 자신을 지원할 수 있습니까?"
"Are you a night owl?"
"당신은 올빼미야?"
"I'm totally a morning person."
"저는 완전히 아침형 인간이에요."
Stuff like that.
그런 것.
What kind of guy asks,
어떤 놈이 물어보는데,
"How much do you weigh?"
"당신의 몸무게는 얼마나 됩니까?"
"What's your waist size?"
"당신의 허리 사이즈는 얼마나 됩니까?"
"What's your body fat percentage?" Would you answer that?
"체지방률이 몇이에요?" 대답해 주시겠습니까?
- Yeah, I would. - Totally.
- 응, 그럴 거야. - 완전히.
We're confident like that.
우리는 그렇게 확신합니다.
I wish someone would ask me, too.
누군가 나에게도 물어봤으면 좋겠다.
He's lived that long, and yet...
그 사람은 그렇게 오래 살았는데도...
What did he give up to have that kind of freedom?
그 사람은 무엇을 포기했나요? 그런 자유를 누리려고?
Money or status?
돈인가, 지위인가?
Yeah.
응.
I don't think I can handle that kind of freedom.
내 생각엔 아닌 것 같아 나는 그런 종류의 자유를 감당할 수 있습니다.
Eat while it's hot.
뜨거울 때 먹습니다.
You burned your tongue, didn't you?
혀에 화상을 입었지, 그렇지?
It's hot.
덥다.
I just don't want to.
나는 단지 원하지 않습니다.
Instead of trying to see
보려고 노력하는 대신
what actually works between you two,
너희 둘 사이에 실제로 무슨 일이 일어나는지,
you're digging up everything that doesn't.
당신은 그렇지 않은 모든 것을 파헤치고 있습니다.
You're way too picky.
당신은 너무 까다롭습니다.
I'm not digging. It's just obvious.
나는 파고 있지 않습니다. 그것은 분명합니다.
Obvious how?
어떻게요?
Are you playing Tetris right now?
지금 테트리스 게임 중이신가요?
Do you really think someone will fit into all your gaps?
정말 그렇게 생각하시나요? 누군가가 당신의 모든 틈새에 들어맞을까요?
You keep waiting for that long I-shaped block,
저 긴 I자형 블록을 계속 기다리시는데,
and then it's game over.
그리고 게임은 끝났습니다.
Do you really think
정말 그렇게 생각하시나요?
someone will ever make her fall for him like that?
누군가가 그녀를 만들 것이다 그 사람한테 그렇게 반했어?
Rather than making her fall for him...
그녀를 그 사람에게 반하게 만들기보다는...
Oh, it's empty. She'd need a miracle to fall in love.
아, 비어 있어요. 그녀가 사랑에 빠지려면 기적이 필요할 것이다.
Get us another drink.
한잔 더 주세요.
Give me a second.
잠시만 기다려 주세요.
I thought you only dated guys
난 당신이 남자들만 데이트하는 줄 알았는데
if they were good-looking.
그들이 잘생겼다면.
I thought so too...
나도 그렇게 생각했는데...
But I'm more practical than I look.
하지만 나는 보기보다 실용적이다.
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
Is that really all?
정말 그게 다야?
Actually...
사실...
I was sure of one thing.
나는 한 가지를 확신했다.
About what?
무엇에 대해서?
That you would...
당신은 ...
need me.
내가 필요해.
I once heard that
언젠가 그런 말을 들었어
liking someone starts with...
누군가를 좋아하는 것은 시작부터...
watching them.
그들을 지켜보고 있습니다.
And I...
그리고 나는...
I found myself...
나는 나 자신을 발견했다 ...
watching you without meaning to.
의미 없이 당신을 지켜보고 있습니다.
Almost every day.
거의 매일.
You looked lonely.
당신은 외로워 보였습니다.
You.
너.
Like...
마치...
You looked like someone...
당신은 누군가처럼 보였습니다 ...
trying to be lonely.
외로워지려고 노력 중입니다.
But, well...
하지만 글쎄...
No one really chooses that on purpose.
일부러 그런 걸 선택하는 사람은 아무도 없어요.
[Next Door Guy]
[옆집 남자]
Did you get home safely?
집에 무사히 잘 도착하셨나요?
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Okay. Wait for me.
좋아요. 기다려주세요.
Let's talk there.
거기에 대해 이야기합시다.
We ran into each other again.
우리는 다시 서로를 만났습니다.
I couldn't reach you, so I was worried.
연락이 안 돼서 걱정이 됐어요.
Did I do something wrong last time?
지난번에 제가 뭔가 잘못했나요?
No.
아니요.
Was it the food we had? Was it bad?
우리가 먹었던 음식이었어? 나빴나요?
I thought...
나는 생각했다 ...
we felt pretty...
우리 기분이 꽤 좋았는데...
natural together.
자연스럽게 함께.
Like we clicked.
우리가 클릭한 것처럼요.
How do we click?
어떻게 클릭하나요?
Well...
음...
I mean...
내 말은 ...
I thought we...
내 생각엔 우리가...
could grow into it.
그것으로 성장할 수 있습니다.
Get to know each other more.
서로를 더 알아가세요.
Thinking about it now,
지금 생각해보면,
your silence was an answer in itself.
당신의 침묵은 그 자체로 대답이었습니다.
It's not just you.
당신뿐만이 아닙니다.
I don't want to get to know anyone.
나는 누구와도 알고 싶지 않습니다.
[Jeju Travel Voucher]
[제주여행상품권]
Does this even make sense?
이게 말이 되나요?
Huh?
뭐?
You booked it to go with Mom.
엄마랑 같이 가려고 예약했잖아.
Then obviously you cancel it.
그러면 당연히 취소합니다.
Why don't you take Dad to Jeju instead?
대신 아빠를 제주도로 데려가는 게 어때요?
If you want to go, you go.
가고 싶으면 가세요.
- I have to work. - I'm also busy.
- 일해야 해요. - 나도 바빠요.
Jun Seo.
서준.
- I... - Aren't you sad at all?
- 나는... - 전혀 슬프지 않나요?
Huh?
뭐?
Why does no one seem sad?
왜 아무도 슬퍼 보이지 않는 걸까요?
Why?
왜?
I've been...
나는 ...
since the day your mom had that accident...
네 엄마가 그 사고를 당하신 그날부터...
- for the past seven years... - Are you happy now?
- 지난 7년간.. - 지금은 행복해요?
You want to go to a hotel and celebrate Mom's death?
호텔에 가고 싶으세요? 엄마의 죽음을 축하한다고요?
Hey, watch what you say.
이봐, 말하는 것 좀 봐.
And you...
그리고 당신은 ...
What did you say to Mom before she died?
엄마가 죽기 전에 엄마한테 뭐라고 말했어요?
You said she looked fat.
당신은 그녀가 뚱뚱해 보인다고 말했어요.
I said her clothes looked tight. I didn't call her fat.
나는 그녀의 옷이 타이트해 보인다고 말했다. 나는 그녀를 뚱뚱하다고 부르지 않았습니다.
Don't you regret saying that?
그런 말을 한 것을 후회하지 않나요?
Being sad and feeling guilty aren't the same thing.
슬프고 죄책감을 느끼는 것 같은 것이 아닙니다.
I'm asking if you regret it.
후회하는지 묻고 싶습니다.
What good does regret do?
후회하면 무슨 소용이 있나요?
You should at least regret it.
적어도 후회해야 합니다.
Is this what you meant by "everyone grieves in their own way?"
이게 무슨 뜻인가요? "다들 각자의 방식으로 슬퍼하나요?"
Yeah? You...
응? 당신은...
You think everything was hard because of Mom?
엄마 때문에 모든 게 힘들었을 것 같아?
You're just like her.
당신은 그녀와 똑같습니다.
You both act like you're the only ones hurting.
당신들 둘 다 당신만 아픈 것처럼 행동합니다.
You're both selfish.
너희 둘 다 이기적이야.
But at least...
하지만 적어도...
Mom wasn't a coward like you.
엄마는 너처럼 겁쟁이가 아니었어.
You ran away.
당신은 도망갔습니다.
You didn't move out because you were strong.
당신은 강했기 때문에 이사를 나간 것이 아닙니다.
You just wanted to escape this house, right?
넌 그냥 이 집에서 탈출하고 싶었어, 그렇지?
[Operating Room]
[수술실]
Mom.
엄마.
Let's go to the hospital.
병원에 가자.
Let's go together.
함께 가자.
I'm not going.
나는 가지 않을 것이다.
You're not going to do rehab?
재활은 안 할 건가요?
How am I supposed to do rehab without legs?
다리가 없는 재활은 어떻게 해야 하나요?
Fine.
괜찮은.
Even if you don't go to the hospital,
병원에 가지 않더라도
you need to wash your face and your hair.
얼굴과 머리를 씻어야 해요.
Get up.
일어나세요.
No.
아니요.
Mom, are you giving up on life?
엄마, 인생을 포기하시나요?
Is this because of me?
이게 나 때문인가요?
You think this happened because of me, right?
나 때문에 이런 일이 벌어졌다고 생각하는 거 맞지?
So you're trying to fall apart just to prove a point to me?
그래서 넌 무너지려고 하는 거야 단지 나에게 요점을 증명하기 위해?
- Get out. - I told you not to come...
- 나가세요. - 오지 말라고 했는데..
- because it was raining! - Get out! I said get out!
- 비가 왔거든요! - 나가세요! 나가라고 했어요!
Why did you come and do this to me?
왜 와서 나한테 이런 짓을 한 거야?
Get out!
나가세요!
Jun Kyung.
준경.
You can't just leave like this.
이대로 떠날 수는 없습니다.
Your mom's heart will ache. Talk it out before you go.
엄마 마음이 아프실 거예요. 가기 전에 얘기해 보세요.
Later.
나중에.
Hey, Jun Kyung.
안녕하세요, 준경님.
I wanted to tell my past self
과거의 나에게 말하고 싶었어
not to let her go.
그녀를 놓아주지 않기 위해.
I wanted to grab her
나는 그녀를 붙잡고 싶었다
and tell her to stop.
그리고 그녀에게 그만하라고 말하세요.
If you run away now,
지금 도망치면
you'll keep running forever.
당신은 영원히 계속 달릴 것입니다.
You'll keep pretending you're fine,
넌 계속 괜찮은 척 할 거야
and acting like nothing's wrong.
그리고 아무 일도 없는 것처럼 행동합니다.
You'll keep...
당신은 계속...
being...
존재...
alone.
혼자.
Yeah.
응.
Are you drinking alone again?
또 혼자 술을 마시시나요?
We're about to open a bottle of wine.
이제 와인 한 병을 개봉하려고 합니다.
Come over to our place.
우리 집으로 오세요.
Right...
오른쪽...
I always ran to your place.
나는 항상 당신의 집으로 달려갔습니다.
Pardon?
뭐라고요?
Maybe Hyeong Jun is right.
어쩌면 형준이 맞을 수도 있겠네요.
I don't think I can do anything on my own.
나는 혼자서 아무것도 할 수 없다고 생각합니다.
I can't fight.
나는 싸울 수 없습니다.
I can't make up.
나는 화해할 수 없다.
I can't comfort anyone... or be comforted.
나는 누구도 위로할 수 없고... 위로받을 수도 없습니다.
The only thing I can do alone
혼자 할 수 있는 유일한 일은
is be lonely.
외로워요.
Hey.
여기요.
Do you want me to come over?
내가 여기 오기를 바라나요?
No.
아니요.
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
I'm okay tonight.
오늘 밤은 괜찮습니다.
Jun Kyung?
준경?
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
Huh?
뭐?
There's nothing for you
당신을 위한 건 아무것도 없어요
to apologize for.
사과하려고.
I mean...
내 말은 ...
Well...
음...
You mean what?
무슨 말이에요?
I wasn't being honest.
나는 정직하지 않았습니다.
I always hide how I feel and lie about it.
나는 늘 내 기분을 숨기고 거짓말을 한다.
So...
그래서...
I mean...
내 말은 ...
I want to get to know you.
나는 당신을 알고 싶습니다.
Weren't you the one
당신은 아니었나요?
who said you didn't want to get to know anyone?
당신이 누구와도 알고 싶지 않다고 누가 말했습니까?
I want to try.
나는 시도하고 싶다.
If it's not too late.
너무 늦지 않았다면.
It's late now.
지금은 늦었어요.
But I think there's still a chance.
하지만 아직 기회는 있다고 생각해요.
So... what do we do now?
그럼... 이제 우리는 무엇을 할까요?
Well...
음...
Let's take it slow.
천천히 해보자.
Okay.
좋아요.
Slowly.
느리게.
Do you want to come in for a bit?
잠깐 들어가 볼래?
No.
아니요.
Slowly.
천천히.
Okay.
좋아요.
I portioned the beef soup and put it in the freezer.
나는 쇠고기 수프를 나누어 먹었다 그리고 냉동실에 넣으세요.
Don't skip meals, and make sure you lock the door.
식사를 거르지 마세요. 그리고 문을 꼭 잠그세요.
Yoon Sol, you nailed it today.
윤솔씨, 오늘 수고하셨어요.
Did you fall for me?
나한테 반했나요?
"Fall for me?"
"나한테 반했어?"
What the...
뭐야...
- I'm Joo Hyun Kyung. - I see.
- 주현경 입니다. - 알겠어요.
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
Mr. Seo Jin Ho?
서진호 선생님?
Yeah, that's me.
응, 그게 나야.
Is Mrs. Kim Mi Ran not coming?
김미란 선생님은 안 오시나요?
Well...
음...
There's something going on.
무슨 일이 일어나고 있어요.
Would it be okay if I went alone?
혼자 가도 괜찮을까요?
Life...
인생...
never lets either its brightest blessings
가장 밝은 축복을 결코 허용하지 않습니다
or its deepest sorrows
또는 가장 깊은 슬픔
stay with us for long.
오래오래 함께해주세요.
More than crushing sorrow,
슬픔을 짓누르는 것보다
What is this?
이것은 무엇입니까?
it's the anger that makes my heart race that matters to me.
그것은 분노가 만드는 것입니다 나에게 중요한 것은 내 심장 경주입니다.
That's interesting.
흥미롭네요.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
I've never seen anyone wear dress shoes on a trip.
나는 누구도 본 적이 없다 여행갈 때는 정장 구두를 신으세요.
More than crushing sorrow,
슬픔을 짓누르는 것보다
You look cool.
당신은 멋지다.
those small, unexpected flutters matter more in our lives.
그 작고 예상치 못한 설렘 우리 삶에서 더 중요한 것입니다.
They never let either bright blessings
그들은 결코 밝은 축복을 허락하지 않습니다
or crushing sorrow
또는 참을 수 없는 슬픔
stay with us
우리와 함께하세요
for long.
오랫동안
That's life.
그것이 인생입니다.
- A house party? - Yes.
- 하우스 파티요? - 예.
How about we have my birthday at your place?
내 생일을 당신 집에서 보내는 게 어때요?
Is this what you meant by everyone grieving in their own way?
이게 무슨 뜻인가요? 다들 각자의 방식으로 슬퍼하고 있나요?
I'm a total lost cause.
나는 완전히 잃어버린 원인입니다.
I'm glad you came.
당신이 와줘서 기뻐요.
That's good for you.
그것은 당신에게 좋습니다.
It feels like I'm the only one living well without her.
나만 그런 것 같아 그 사람 없이도 잘 살아요.
It makes me feel so guilty...
너무 죄책감이 들게 만드네요...
and it hurts so much.
너무 아파요.
Mr. Seo?
서 선생님?
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
We said...
우리는 말했다...
we'd take it slow, right?
천천히 하자, 그렇지?
Is it really that good?
정말 그렇게 좋은가요?
I knew it.
나는 그것을 알고 있었다.
When one becomes two, things get complicated.
하나가 둘이 되면 상황이 복잡해진다.
You won't regret getting to know me, will you?
나를 알게 된 것을 후회하지 않을 거에요, 그렇죠?
I'm going crazy, wondering why I ever liked you,
미칠 것 같아 궁금해 내가 왜 당신을 좋아했는지,
why I trusted someone like you.
내가 왜 당신 같은 사람을 믿었는지.